SULTAN KHAN

Software Developer



Bhiwandi, Thane



+91 7769893379



sultankhan1401s@gmail.com



SUMMARY

Looking for a challenging and growth-oriented career where my knowledge is used to impact organization goals and at the same time enrich my profession and skills Eager Python Django developer with 2+ years exploiting modeltemplate-view architectural pattern of Django framework to shorten development times and reduce design costs.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Django Developer

September 2023 - Present | Redshire Matrix Pvt. Ltd. - Delhi, India

- Increased website performance by optimizing front-end and back-end code for faster loading times.
- Ensured data security by implementing robust authentication and authorization mechanisms on both client-side and server-side applications.
- Managed development milestones from initial steps through final delivery.

Software Developer

August 2022 - September 2023 | RhythmFlows Solutions Pvt. Ltd. -Pune, India

- Enhanced user experience through designing and implementing user-friendly interfaces.
- Increased development speed by automating repetitive tasks using scripts and tools.
- Contributed to a positive team environment through effective communication, problem-solving, and collaboration skills.

Junior Python Developer

January 2022 - July 2022 | Softcell Technologies Global Pvt. Ltd. -Mumbai, India

- Improved application performance by optimizing Python code and implementing best practices.
- Streamlined the software development process with Agile methodologies and effective communication among team members.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design, develop, and implement high-quality Python applications.

CERTIFICATIONS

Python Full Stack Developer, Dcodetech Industrial Training (OPC) Pvt.Ltd - 6 Months

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Backend

- Python
- Django
- Django Rest Framework
- FastAPI

Front-End

- Javascript
- Angular

Database

- PostgreSQL
- ⇒ MySQL

Version Control Systems

- **⊃** Git
- GitHub

Opreting Systems

- Windows
- **○** Linux

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (Information Technology)

University of Mumbai Oct 2020

Final Percentage: 67.40%

Higher Secondary Certificate

Maharashtra Board

Feb 2017

Percentage: 47.88%

Secondary School Certificate

Maharashtra Board

March 2015

Percentage: 56.80%

PROJECTS

Book Review:

Can Read, Download, update, review in addition, can Login, Register, Password Reset Through mail, API of All Book. Also, admin have more authority admin can delete books delete review and more.

Technologies used: Django, DRF, SQLite3

Task Management:

This is a web-app created using Django Framework for daily TaskAssignment The feature of this app 3 level users, Superadmin ,Team Leader and employees with different level of permission. Superadmin have right to add new user to the portal. The leader has the permission to assign task to their team members and the employee on login get the List of tasks Assigned, Status and Due Date. The task Status, List of Completed/Pending Task

Technologies used: Django, PostgreSQL

Budgeting Solution:

The proposed Budgeting Solution provides facility to create and maintainBudget (AOP) on Expenses tracking side and provide facility to enter provisions and compare provisions data with actuals data. Post implementation of Budgeting solution BFL (The budgeting) team will beable to collate budgeting rules in line with business requirements and upload business data and arrive at AOP and its revision and comparison with provisions seamlessly.

Technologies used: Angular14, DRF, PostgreSQL

MIS Dashboard:

The proposed Management Information System (MIS) dashboard to daily bank reports based on trial balance and shadow file. Asper requirement we present lots of reports like deposit Summary and deposit Summary. Provide an option to export the display data in format like Excel and Pdf also. Created Admin interface for user management and configured Organize file structure for read trial and shadow files. Set up SFTP server for secure file transfer.

Technologies used: Angular14, DRF, PostgreSQL

Order Management:

Create RESTful APIs or other communication protocols that allow front-end applications and other services to interact with the order management system. These APIs should provide the necessary endpoints for actions like orders, orders order history, and category and product listing according user.

Technologies used: Angular14, DRF, PostgreSQL

LANGUAGE

- EnglishIntermediate
- → Hindi Bilingual or Proficient
- MarathiIntermediate
- UrduIntermediate

PROFESSIONAL SKILL

- Leadership
- Teamwork and Collaboration
- ⇒ Problem-Solving
- Adaptability
- Creativity

INTERESTS

- Learning New Things
- Playing and watching Cricket
- Open Source Contributions
- New Technology Exploration
- Code Challenges and Competitions
- Cycling